zenphoto.org 2018-01-26

# Data Privacy Policy | Zenphoto - The simpler media website CMS

## Data Privacy Policy

Our website may be used without entering personal information. Different rules may apply to certain services on our site, however, and are explained separately below. We collect personal information from you (e.g. name, address, email address, telephone number, etc.) in accordance with the provisions of German data protection statutes. Information is considered personal if it can be associated exclusively to a specific natural person. The legal framework for data protection may be found in the German Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG) and the Telemedia Act (TMG). The provisions below serve to provide information as to the manner, extent and purpose for collecting, using and processing personal information by the provider.

**Malte Müller** **malte@zenphoto.org**

Please be aware that data transfer via the internet is subject to security risks and, therefore, complete protection against third-party access to transferred data cannot be ensured.

#### Cookies

Our website makes use of so-called cookies in order to recognize repeat use of our website by the same user/internet connection subscriber. Cookies are small text files that your internet browser downloads and stores on your computer. They are used to improve our website and services. In most cases these are so-called "session cookies" that are deleted once you leave our website.

To an extent, however, these cookies also pass along information used to automatically recognize you. Recognition occurs through an IP address saved to the cookies. The information thereby obtained is used to improve our services and to expedite your access to the website.

You can prevent cookies from being installed by adjusting the settings on your browser software accordingly. You should be aware, however, that by doing so you may not be able to make full use of all the functions of our website.

#### Server Data

For technical reasons, data such as the following, which your internet browser transmits to us or to our web space provider (so called server log files), is collected: - type and version of the browser you use - operating system - websites that linked you to our site (referrer URL) - websites that you visit - date and time of your visit - your Internet Protocol (IP) address. This anonymous data is stored separately from any personal information you may have provided, thereby making it impossible to connect it to any particular person. The data is used for statistical purposes in order to improve our website and services.

#### Purpose of Registering

We offer you the opportunity to sign up for our website. The information entered when signing up, as shown in the registration form

**User name and email address**

is collected and stored solely for use by our website. When signing up for our website, we also store your IP address (anyonmized, first two numbers only) and the date and time you registered. This serves to protect us in the event a third party improperly and without your knowledge makes use of your data to sign up for our site. None of this information is transferred to third parties. Nor is any of this information matched to any information that may be collected by other components of our website.

#### Contacting Us

On our website we offer you the opportunity to contact us, either by email and/or by using a contact form. In such event, information provided by the user is stored for the purpose of facilitating communications with the user. No data is transferred to third parties. Nor is any of this information matched to any information that may be collected by other components of our website.

#### Posting Comments

On our website we offer you the opportunity to post comments about individual articles. For this purpose, the IP address (anyonmized, first two numbers only) of the user/internet connection subscriber is stored. This information is stored for our security in the event the author through his/her comments infringes against third party rights and/or unlawful content is entered. Consequently, we have a direct interest in the author’s stored data, particularly since we may be potentially liable for such violations. No data is transferred to third parties. Nor is any of this information matched to any information that may be collected by other components of our website.

#### Use of reCAPTCHA

In order to protect input forms on our site, we use the “reCAPTCHA” service of Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043 USA, hereinafter "Google." By means of this service it can be distinguished whether the corresponding input is of human origin or is created improperly by automated machine processing.

To our knowledge, the referrer URL, the IP address, the behaviour of the website visitors, information about the operating system, browser and length of stay, cookies, display instructions and scripts, user input behaviour and mouse movements in the “reCAPTCHA” checkbox are conveyed to “Google.”

Google uses the information obtained, among other things, to digitize books and other printed matter as well as to optimize services such as Google Street View and Google Maps (e.g. house number and street name recognition).

The IP address provided as part of “reCAPTCHA” is not merged with other data from Google unless you are logged into your Google Account at the time the "reCAPTCHA" plug-in is used. If you want to prevent this transmission and storage of data by “Google” about you and your behaviour on our website, you must log out of “Google” before you visit our site or before using the reCAPTCHA plug-in.

The use of the “reCAPTCHA” service is according to the Google Terms of Use: 

<https://www.google.com/intl/de/policies/privacy/>.

#### Use of the web analysis service PIWIK

Our website uses the web analysis service PIWIK. To carry out this analysis, PIWIK uses cookies. Cookies are small text files that are stored to your computer and provide analysis of your use of the site. The information generated by these cookies, such as time, place and frequency of your visits to our site, including your IP address, are transmitted to our PIWIK server and stored there. As part of this process, you IP address is immediately anonymized so that you as user remain anonymous to us. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this site is not transferred to third parties. You can prevent cookies from being installed by adjusting the settings on your browser software accordingly. You should be aware, however, that by doing so you may not be able to make full use of all the functions of our website.

Should you be unwilling to have this data about your use of the site stored and analyzed, you may at any time subsequently withdraw your consent to it being stored and used with a click of the mouse. A so-called opt-out cookie is then placed on your browser, and as a result Piwik will no longer collect any data on your visits. Please be aware that, should you delete cookies from your browser settings, the opt-out cookie from PIWIK may also be deleted and will need to be reactivated.

#### Use of YouTube components with enhanced data protection mode

On our website we use components (videos) of YouTube, LLC 901 Cherry Ave., 94066 San Bruno, CA, USA, a company belonging to Google Inc., Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA.

To this end, we use the “ - enhanced data protection mode - ” option provided by YouTube.

When you display a page that has an embedded video, a connection will be made to the YouTube server and the content will appear on the website via a communication to your browser.

According to the information provided by YouTube, in “ - enhanced data protection mode -”, data is only transferred to the YouTube server, in particular which of our websites you have visited, if you watch the video. If you are logged onto YouTube at the same time, this information will be matched to your YouTube member account. You can prevent this from happening by logging out of your member account before visiting our website.

Further information about data protection by YouTube is provided by Google under the following link:

<https://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy/>

#### Use of Vimeo components

We use Vimeo components on our site.  Vimeo is a service of Vimeo LCC, 555 West 18th Street, New York, New York 10011, USA. Whenever you visit our website, which is equipped with such a component, this component causes the browser you are using to download a corresponding display of the Vimeo component. When you visit our site and are at the same time logged into Vimeo, Vimeo recognizes by means of the information collected by the component, which specific page you are visiting and assigns this information to your personal account at Vimeo. If, for example, you click on the “Play” button or make comments, this information will be conveyed to your personal user account at Vimeo and stored there. In addition, the information that you have visited our site will be passed on to Vimeo. This is done regardless of whether you click on the component/comment or not.

If you want to prevent this transmission and storage of data by Vimeo about you and your behaviour on our website, you must log out of Vimeo before you visit our site. Vimeo’s Privacy Policy provides more detailed information concerning this, in particular regarding the collection and use of data by Vimeo: <https://vimeo.com/privacy>

#### Use of affilinet tracking cookies

Our website employs affilinet tracking cookies in order to correctly record sales and/or leads. Cookies are small text files that are saved to your computer when you visit a website. These affilinet tracking cookies do not store personal data of any kind. Instead, it only collects the identification number of the intermediary partner as well as the reference number of the advertising material that was clicked on by the visitor to the website. This information is required in order to process the payment transaction between the website operator and the advertiser. The partner identification number serves to designate the intermediary partner to which a commission is to be paid once a transaction has been concluded. You can prevent cookies from being installed by adjusting the settings on your browser software accordingly. You should be aware, however, that by doing so you may not be able to make full use of all the functions of our website. 

### Information/Cancellation/Deletion

On the basis of the Federal Data Protection Act, you may contact us at no cost if you have questions relating to the collection, processing or use of your personal information, if you wish to request the correction, blocking or deletion of the same, or if you wish to cancel explicitly granted consent. Please note that you have the right to have incorrect data corrected or to have personal data deleted, where such claim is not barred by any legal obligation to retain this data.

[Sample Data Privacy Policy Statement](https://www.ratgeberrecht.eu/leistungen/muster-datenschutzerklaerung.html) provided by the [Law Offices of Weiß & Partner](https://www.ratgeberrecht.eu/)

#### Appendix: Contributor pages

We always create such a page for you if an extension or theme is listed on our site or if you contribtuted any significant fix/patch to a release. We differ three main categories that are listed on our "About us" section:

  * **Official and active team members** (this traditionally includes our regular translators)
  * **Former team members**
  * **Contributors**

Of course we don’t expose any data or info you haven’t published yourself in public already via your contributions like on GitHub, our forum or your third party theme or plugin itself. Needless to say, you can request changes or even have your page removed at any time. We don’t and won’t use your data for anything else.

This is what we list:

  * **Screen name:**  The alias or screen name you appeared to us via e.g. the forum, GitHub or our your third party theme or plugin itself.
  * **Real name:**  If we know that via your contributions or website.
  * **Website:  **If we know it. Can be a GitHub page or social media profile as well.
  * **Short description:**  Only used for active or former team members who provided it themselves.

Additionally we automatically list all  **plugins, themes or releases**  you ever contributed to and that have entries on our site. We can do that because all your entries are assigned by a special tag _author_ <screen name>_. You can see that tag below each extension entry (on themes we don't list tags specifcally).

We have done that for quite some time already to show the "More by author" below each theme or extension entry.  _< screen name>_ is also the name of your page in the url (titlelink). Also, every theme or extension entry now has a box that lists its authors and links to each profile page.

Again, the Zenphoto team will not use the information you enter for anything else than what you see:

  1. Showcase and credit your contributions.
  2. Gather general statistics of contributions to satisfy our and your curiosity.
  3. Easier maintenance of author credits as we don’t have to change multiple entries if a user name or website link changes.
  4. You will never get advertisement mass mails or anything else.
  5. We will never give your data to third parties or use it for commercial purposes.
